Kettle bells are one of the best tools
for full body workouts. They're time
efficient, plus they're going to train
your strength and conditioning at the
same time. Now, they come in many shapes
and sizes, but today we're going to be
talking about the competition kettle
bells from Kettle Bell Kings. I hope
y'all are ready cuz we got a lot to talk
about. Let's get right to it.
[Music]
What's up y'all? It's Jake back in the
bar and garage gym. In this video, I'm
going to tell you everything you need to
know about this kettle bell. From the
price, the features, some of my pros and
cons, most importantly, who should or
maybe should not scoop one of these bad
boys up. Now, before I start doing all
that, got to let you know we've reviewed
a ton of kettle bells on barb.com. And
since we're so nice, we went ahead and
did the hard part for you and compiled a
list of the best kettle bells that are
on the market. So if you want to check
that out, all you got to do is search
barbin best kettle bells. Our list is
going to pull up. You can find out for
yourself which one cracks that number
one spot.
Okay, so what exactly is a competition
kettle bell? Well, just, you know,
summarize it really quick. Competition
kettle bells are standardized in sizing.
All right. So, actual bell is not going
to be determined by the weight like it
is with a cast iron bell. So, we have a
35lb bell right here. That 9 lb bell,
it's going to be the same size as this
one. And the same goes, you know, as you
go up in weight. Now, the handle
diameter is also going to be thinner
than with the cast iron bell. And it's
also closer to the actual bell. So, with
the cast iron one, it sits up higher, if
that makes sense. Now, because of the
standardized sizing, you're really able
to focus on your technique and perfect
that technique, which is obviously a
crucial aspect because you don't want to
be doing your lifts the wrong way and
potentially injure yourself. Now,
because of that, you know, higher
standard of quality and everything, you
are going to have to pay a higher price
tag, which is something, you know, just
to keep in mind. Now, enough of that.
Let's talk about what I like about these
competition kettle bells. All right, so
in addition to the uniform size of these
competition kettle bells, I also really
like how they're colorcoded. you know,
based on their specific weight. It's
just a really nice touch. Kind of takes,
you know, the thinking out of
everything, you can just grab your
kettle bell once you know what each
weight represents and get straight to
your workout. I really like how they're
legal for kettle bell sport
competitions. So, you know, if you are
competing in that or maybe you want to,
you know, you're able to really train
from home with these, which is a nice
touch. And then also, I like how they
have the hollow core right here, which
is really going to, you know, lead to a
perfectly balanced kettle bell.
[Music]
Now, when it comes to those cons, we got
to talk about money. You know, as I
mentioned, competition kettle bells are
more expensive than cast iron kettle
bells. Something, you know, you
definitely want to keep in mind if you
don't want to spend as much money as you
want to on this one. This one's about
120 bucks. You know, you can definitely
go the cast iron route and save you some
money. The bare steel handle might not
work for everybody. I personally like
it. It feels pretty good in my hands.
You know, I'm able to get a good grip.
But I say it all the time. I'm going to
say it again. You texture is personal
preference. So, you know, what works for
me just might not work for you. You
know, definitely just keep that in mind.
There's actually six kettle bells here
that are not technically competition
standards. So, the 4, 6, 8, 36, 40, and
44 kilogram bells, they actually have a
smaller window size right here, which,
you know, prevents them from being
competition standard. So, definitely
keep that in mind. And then lastly, you
know, the packaging wasn't the best.
Now, it's tough, you know, to ship a
kettle bell in general. They're always
just in, you know, a cardboard box. But,
you know, with this one specifically,
that box was kind of destroyed whenever
I got it, which led to, you know, a lot
of chips in this kettle bell right here.
Now, I personally don't mind. You know,
it it's still going to work the exact
same. I'm still going to get the same
amount of usage out of it. it just might
not be as aesthetically pleasing as it
would be if you know that packaging was
a little bit better. So definitely just
keep that in mind. You know, it might
not be as you know brand spanking new
looking as you would like.
All right, now I want to touch on
pricing again with the Bells of Steel
Competition Kettle Bells. And these are
going to range from 50 bucks up to $470.
I'm not going to list every single one
of them out, but this 35 lb bell we have
right here is going to cost you right
around 120 bucks. And remember, you
know, with all products, you know, that
price can definitely fluctuate over
time. So, definitely keep that in mind.
Now, these are arguably the most
expensive competition kettle bells that
are on the market, but that's because of
that shipping is included in that base
price tag essentially, right? So, they
don't actually charge for shipping, but
you know, when you compare to a company
like Rogue and you go and check out
their competition kettle bells, you
know, they're cheaper with that base
price, but then you got to pay for
shipping, which winds up making it a
little bit more expensive. So, at the
end of the day, you know, compared to
competition kettle bells, these are
actually, you know, a pretty nice price
tag considering the overall quality. Of
course, you can find some cheaper ones.
I can't, you know, attest to the quality
of those like I can with this bad boy
right here. Now, 120 bucks, still a good
amount of money. If you don't want to
spend that much money on one single
kettle bell, I would suggest going after
a cast iron one. You can get one from
Onet for around 70 bucks, I think, right
now. So, definitely, you know, keep all
those things in mind.
All right, so I want to break down the
build really quick with these kettle
bells and let's talk about the handles
and the window size right here. All
right. So, the 10 through 32 and the 48
kg bells have a window of 60 mm and a
handle diameter of 35 mm. While the 4,
6, and 8 kg bells have a 58 mm window
and a handle diameter of 34 mm. Now,
that's, you know, those smaller sizes,
you know, that's perfect for beginners.
It's going to allow you to, you know,
really learn proper hand placement and
technique before you, you know, go up in
weight. And it's not too far off, which
is, you know, really nice. It's not like
you're going to have like a massive
learning curve or anything like that,
which is pretty cool. Now, Bells of
Steel uses a dual cast process that
involves two molds. Now, there's not any
welding or any plugs or anything like
that right there. But this kind of leads
to this hollowedout core, which is
really nice. It's going to eliminate the
possibility of kettle rattle, which you
know happens when other companies will,
you know, take scrap metal basically and
weld it within and that kind of comes
loose after you repeatedly drop the
bell, which tends to happen a lot
whenever you're doing kettle bell
workouts. Now, the actual bell is
uniform in size all across the board,
which is really nice. You know, you can
keep that same technique across all of
your lifts, which is just a really nice
thing right there. They're also
colorcoded depending on the weight,
which is, you know, a nice touch. you're
able to, you know, just grab and go with
your weight. And then once again, you
know, you do have this bare steel handle
right here, which I personally think
gives you a really solid grip.
All right, so I just want to show you
guys, you know, a few things up close
with this competition kettle bell. Now,
once again, you know, at the top, you do
have your bare steel handle. I like it.
It gives me, you know, a really solid
grip. Some people may prefer cast iron,
but this really gets the job done for
me. This handle diameter is 35
millimeters and the window right here is
60 mm. So, this does in fact meet, you
know, those competition standards. It's
really nice and you're really able to,
you know, get your hand in there and
stack your wrist the way you're supposed
to across all of your kettle bell
workouts, you know, which is a really
nice thing. You get that identical hand
placement and everything. Now, this is
yellow to, you know, identify, signal,
you know, whatever you want to call it.
35 pounds. You know, every single one of
these kettle bells, you know, is in fact
colorcoded based on that weight, which
is really nice. And the actual, you
know, size of the bell is not going to
change across the board. It's another
really nice thing right there. You know,
allows you to continue to have that, you
know, identical hand placement,
identical technique. That way, you're
able to get that perfect technique,
which is, you know, something you
definitely want. Now, in terms of
aesthetics, you know, as you can see,
you know, as I mentioned, you know,
there's some chipping right here. It's
really bad on this other side right
here. You know, it's not that big of a
deal. It's not going to change anything
with the kettle bell. It's still going
to work the exact same. Still going to
be able to do all the same workouts.
It's just not as aesthetically pleasing
maybe as some people might like. It's
going to be okay though. And then as we
flip it over right here, I like this,
you know, wide base right here. It's
going to keep it nice and flat and
balanced, should I say. Now, also once
again, you know, you do have this
hollowed out core. Now, a cast iron bell
is not like that. you know, some
competition kettle bells of lesser
quality aren't like that. This is really
nice. You know, it's going to allow you
to have that, you know, perfectly
balanced weight, which is, you know, a
really good thing specifically with
these workouts.
[Music]
Now, I think this is an ideal purchase
for anybody who, you know, a, you know,
competes in kettle bell sport or maybe
wants to compete in kettle bell sport
and you're looking for a nice way to
practice at home. This is going to be a
really solid option for you because, you
know, these do meet competition
standards. Other than a few of them,
obviously, but the majority of these
kettle bells meet competition standards.
And then also, you know, if you're just
wanting to have, you know, that proper
technique and identical hand placement
across all of your lifts, you know,
regardless of the weight size, I think
you're really going to like the fact
that these are all, you know,
standardized in their sizing, which is
the case with all competition kettle
bells, but just a really nice thing
right there. Now, however, you know, the
texture might not be the best for
everybody. You know, some people prefer
the cast iron kettle bells, just the
grip that it provides you. And then also
like if you don't care about size
staying the same, you're probably going
to be better off going with a cast iron
kettle bell. And that's, you know,
certainly true again with cast iron
kettle bells with the pricing because
they're going to be cheaper than a
competition kettle bell. And then
lastly, you know, if you're tight on
space and you don't have enough room to
have, you know, multiple kettle bells
laying around all over the floor, you
might be better off going after an
adjustable kettle bell system, which
Bells of Steel actually has one that you
might want to check out.
[Music]
That's all I got for y'all today on the
Bells of Steel Competition kettle bells.
You know, they're going to be more
expensive than a cast iron bell. If you
don't have enough space to, you know,
house multiple of them, might be better
off with adjustable kettle bell system
like I mentioned a minute ago. At the
end of the day though, you know, I
really think the uniform size, you know,
all across is really nice. I like the
bare steel handles right here. Gives me
a pretty pretty solid grip. And also,
you know, this hollowed out core just
leads to a perfectly balanced product.
Thanks for watching, y'all. Hope this
video was helpful. I was able to answer
any questions you may have about these
kettle bells. As always, keep your eyes
peeled for my next video. For now, why
don't you head over to barbend.com cuz
we have a full written article just
waiting for you to read it. All you do
is search barbells of steel competition
kettle bell review. You'll find all the
details and everything we discussed here
today. I'll catch youall next time.
[Music]
[Applause]